John Howard Society of the Lower Mainland of British Columbia fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- General administrative and office files, 1934 - 1990; F-1-3; 3.08 m of textual records
  - Resource clients, 1967 - 1990; F-1-3-4; 38 cm of textual records
    - Electronic monitoring program advisory committee, 1990; F-1-3-4-0-27 (Archival box - standard 1-92)
    - Family violence, 1990; F-1-3-4-0-28 (Archival box - standard 1-92)
    - Non-profit organizations, 1990; F-1-3-4-0-29 (Archival box - standard 1-93)
    - Recividism, 1990; F-1-3-4-0-30 (Archival box - standard 1-93)
  - Associated societies, branches, communities, united appeals, 1968 - 1980; F-1-3-5; 50 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files on other offices of the John Howard Society, its National office and regional branches, primarily the North Okanagan Branch and the Kamloops Branch.
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 1 Administration, 1968 - 1971; F-1-3-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-33)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 2 Administration, 1972 - 1974; F-1-3-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-33)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 3 Administration, 1975 - 1976; F-1-3-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-33)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 4 Administration, 1976 - 1977; F-1-3-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-33)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 5 Administration, 1978 - 1979; F-1-3-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-33)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 6 Administration, 1979 - 1980; F-1-3-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 1 Corrections, 1969 - 1975; F-1-3-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - John Howard Society of Canada - Vol. 2 Corrections, 1976 - 1979; F-1-3-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - Okanagan - Mainline Council, 1969 - 1970; F-1-3-5-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - Fraser Valley Operation, 1969 - 1975; F-1-3-5-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - Kamloops (Branch) Vol. 1, 1969 - 1974; F-1-3-5-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - Kamloops (Branch) Vol. 2, 1975 - 1978; F-1-3-5-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-34)
    - Kamloops (Branch) Vol. 3, 1978 - 1980; F-1-3-5-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 1, 1969 - 1972; F-1-3-5-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 2, 1972 - 1973; F-1-3-5-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 3, 1974 - 1975; F-1-3-5-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 4, 1976 - 1977; F-1-3-5-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 5, 1978 - 1980; F-1-3-5-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-35)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Vol. 6, 1979 - 1980; F-1-3-5-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-36)
    - North Okanagan Branch (Vernon) Reports, 1977 - 1980; F-1-3-5-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-36)
    - John Howard Society of Vancouver Island, 1969 - 1977; F-1-3-5-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-36)
- Client Case Files, 1932 - 1980; F-1-4
  Series consists of client case files. Each case file contains personal information about individual clients, as well as a detailed log of the Society's involvement with the client, such as conversations and settings of interviews, analysis, notes, significant facts and/or statements made during the interview. Correspondence with various organizations are also included in the file folder. The arrangement of the files is in a rough alphabetical order.
  In the case of some clients, file folders were not created. Instead, loose documents, usually comprising a 'Face Sheet' and attached sheets providing details of the Society's involvement with the client have been stapled together. These loose documents are clustered in groups and inter filed with foldered case files, arranged in their own rough alphabetical order.
  A separate grouping of client case files have been labeled "Miscellaneous" and are broken down in alphabetical order. These files have been kept separate from other client case files.
  In view of the rough alphabetical order of the client case files and the separate grouping of miscellaneous files, it will be necessary for researchers interested in a particular individual to review a number of different boxes in order to determine the existence of a particular file.
  Arranged according to original order.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release and, as a result of the review, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
- Clients Cards, 1932 - 1980; F-1-5; 1 cm of textual records
  Series consists of client cards on individual clients of the Society, dating mainly from its early period. The client cards are 5 x 8 stock cards containing personal information about individual clients and include details about the Society's involvement with the client. typically included on the cards are sentence and release dates, prison identification numbers, racial origin, education and type of crime committed.
  Cards are arranged numerically by card number. There is no apparent cross-reference between card numbers and client case files. Arranged according to original order.
  There is no index to this material.
  - Parolee card files, [ca 1990] - [ca 1998]; F-1-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
- Habituals files, 1935 - 1986; F-1-6; 41 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to recidivists, also known as 'habituals', also known as repeat offenders, those individuals who were convicted of a crime, released from prison, and then rearrested for a similar arrest.
  Series is arranged into two subseries: Case Files and Assistance Program
  - Habituals case files, 1935-1986; F-1-6-1; 25 cm of textual records
    Series consists of case files relating to recidivists, also known as 'habituals', also known as repeat offenders, those individuals who were convicted of a crime, released from prison, and then rearrested for a similar arrest. Case files include notes made by case workers during regular meetings with recidivists in some cases over decades. Files are arranged alphabetically by individual name but for privacy reasons file titles are limited to acronyms for this series.
    Textual records; Law and justice
    - MA, 1964 - 1982; F-1-6-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - BB, 1984; F-1-6-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - AC, 1935 - 1983; F-1-6-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - TCF, 1965 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - LGF, 1951 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - GG, 1967 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - RH, 1982 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - DH, 1937 - 1985; F-1-6-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - WFH, 1947 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - SH, 1971 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - EM, 1947 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - AM, 1963 - 1976; F-1-6-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-102)
    - PJM, 1956 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - MN, 1970; F-1-6-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - GMP, 1950 - 1981; F-1-6-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - DR, 1984; F-1-6-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - RRS, 1958 - 1985; F-1-6-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - JWS, 1958 - 1963; F-1-6-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - WJS, 1953 - 1983; F-1-6-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - TKS (JV), 1954 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - JT, 1979 - 1984; F-1-6-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
    - JZ, 1955 - 1986; F-1-6-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 1-103)
  - Habituals assistance program, 1984-1985; F-1-6-2; 16 cm of textual records
    Series consists of records relating to a program funded by the federal government to assist those individuals who had been labelled 'habitual offenders' by the courts to end their relationship with the state once the habitual offender classification came to an end.
    - Requests for funding from habituals to government, 1984; F-1-6-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - Correspondence - habituals, 1984; F-1-6-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - Habituals assistance program, 1984; F-1-6-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - MN, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - DJ, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - DO, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - TT, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - GP, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - GK, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - PC, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - SH, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - MA, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - KS, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - WB, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - EM, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-104)
    - AA, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
    - RH, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
    - PM, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
    - WS, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
    - DH, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
    - AA, 1984 - 1985; F-1-6-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
- Victim assistance program, 1981-1988; F-1-7; 18 cm of textual records
  Series consists of victim information sheets, arranged alphabetically. Each form details the name of a victim, the date, the incident in question and follow-up or suggestions for compensation or action.
  - Victim information sheets, 1985 - 1987; F-1-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheets, 1987; F-1-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet A, 1985 - 1988; F-1-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet B, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet C, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet D, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet E, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet F, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet G, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet H, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet I, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet J, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet K, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet L, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet M, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-105)
  - Victim information sheet Mc, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet N, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet O, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet P, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet Q, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet R, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet S, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet T, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet U, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet V, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Victim information sheet W, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
    Pending reviewRestricted in whole
  - Victim information sheet XYZ, 1981 - 1984; F-1-7-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
- Completed community assessments, 1988-1994; F-1-8; 31 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to visitations by JHS staff to the houses of people identified by an offender as a place, person or family of support once the offender is released on parole. Information includes names, birthdates, religious affiliation, race, gender, and general background information of the person or family being interviewed. Series is arranged chronologically.
  - Completed community assessments Jan - Mar, 1992; F-1-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Completed community assessments Oct - Dec, 1991; F-1-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-106)
  - Completed community assessments Jul - Dec, 1991; F-1-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-107)
  - Completed community assessments Apr - Jun, 1991; F-1-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-107)
  - Completed community assessments Oct - Dec, 1992; F-1-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-107)
  - Completed community assessments Apr - Jun, 1992; F-1-8-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-107)
  - Completed community assessments Jan - Mar, 1991; F-1-8-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-108)
  - Completed community assessments Oct - Dec, 1990; F-1-8-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-108)
  - Completed community assessments Jul - Sept, 1990; F-1-8-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-108)
  - Completed community assessments Apr - Jun, 1990; F-1-8-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-108)
  - Completed community assessments Jan - Mar, 1990; F-1-8-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
  - Completed community assessments Oct - Dec, 1989; F-1-8-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
  - Community assessments - summary sheets, 1988 - 1994; F-1-8-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
- Closing reports, 1988-1994; F-1-9; 8 cm of textual records
  Series consists of final reports made by JHS staff on individuals who are completing their parole periods. Information captured in the reports includes personal names, birth dates, general background and current living / working / social conditions of people at the end of their time on parole. Series is arranged chronologically.
  - Suspended cases, 1994; F-1-9-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
  - Closing reports, 1994; F-1-9-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-109)
  - Closing reports, vol. 1, 1993; F-1-9-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-110)
  - Closing reports, vol. 2, 1993; F-1-9-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-110)
  - Closing reports, vol. 3, 1993; F-1-9-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-110)
  - Closing reports - Abbotsford, 1994; F-1-9-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-110)
- Executive Directors records, 1985-1988; F-1-10; 3 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the quasi-personal records of then executive director Bert Massiah. Records include a file of personal correspondence, as well as records relating to liaising with the JHS BC Board of Directors and some other JHS-related correspondence.
  - Personal correspondence, 1985 - 1987; F-1-10-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-93)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1987; F-1-10-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-93)
  - JHS BC board of directors, 1985 - 1988; F-1-10-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-93)
- Annual reports, 2005-2013; F-1-11; 10 textual documents in portable document format (PDF)
  Series consists of annual reports.
  Records in electronic form (born-digital)
  - 2005-2006 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2006-2007 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2007-2008 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2008-2009 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2009-2010 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2010-2011 Annual Report Summary.pdf
  - 2010-2011 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2011-2012 Annual Report Summary.pdf
  - 2011-2012 Annual Report.pdf
  - 2012-2013 Annual Report.pdf
- Articles related to the justice system, 2002-2010; F-1-12; 12 textual records in portable document format (PDF).
  Series consists of articles written, by the JHSLM and others, on various aspects of the justice system in Canada.
  - Desiderata.pdf
  - Prison Is A Place.pdf
  - Best Practices - Housing High-Risk Offenders in the Community (Mar 2010).pdf
  - Conference on Human Trafficking.pdf
  - Practicum Report - Community Services and Youth Court (Aug 2004).pdf
  - Reflections on Attending the Prostitution Offender Program (Dec 2004).pdf
  - Security Certificates (Richards, 2008).pdf
  - Should Prisoners Have the Right to Vote.pdf
  - The Methamphetamine Challenge in Vancouver (Jun 2004).pdf
  - BCYHHA Response.pdf
  - Judicial Review - The Faint Hope Clause (Mar 2005).pdf
  - The Costs of Substance Abuse in Canada 2002_ Highlights.pdf
- Fact sheets, 2013; F-1-13; 12 textual records in portable document format (PDF)
  Series consists of fact sheets published by the JHSLM on correctional facilities, crime and employment, and other matters related to prison advocacy.
  - BC Provincial Corrections - What happens to those serving a provincial sentence in BC (2013).pdf
  - Cost and Crime - A study of BC corrections (2013).pdf
  - Crime and Employment - A guide for job seekers (2013).pdf
  - Crime and Unemployment - Whats the link (2013).pdf
  - Developmental Disabilities and the Law (2013).pdf
  - Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder and the Criminal Justice System - A poor fit (2013).pdf
  - Harm Reduction in Prison and in the Community - Mitigating risks and improving health (2013).pdf
  - Mental Illness and the Law (2013).pdf
  - Public Notifications (2013).pdf
  - Remand and Overcrowding (2013).pdf
  - Tenants and Landlords (2013).pdf
  - Youth and Crime (2013).pdf
- Guides, 2002-2013; F-1-14; 8 textual records in portable document format (PDF)
  Series consists of guides for the youth justice system, families and federal prison, and successful parole applications and release from prison.
  - JHSLM-Family Guide to Federal Corrections in BC (Chinese-Simplified) 2013.pdf
  - JHSLM-Family Guide to Federal Corrections in BC (English) 2013.pdf
  - JHSLM-Family Guide to Federal Corrections in BC (French) 2013.pdf
  - JHSLM-Family Guide to Federal Corrections in BC (Punjabi) 2013.pdf
  - JHSLM-Family Guide to Federal Corrections in BC (Vietnamese) 2013.pdf
  - Guide to Parole Applications - Planning for Success (2008).pdf
  - Planning for Success - Release Planning (Chinese-Simplified) 2013.pdf
  - Planning for Success - Release Planning (English) 2013.pdf
  - Planning for Success - Release Planning (French) 2013.pdf
  - Planning for Success - Release Planning (Punjabi) 2013.pdf
  - Planning for Success - Release Planning (Vietnamese) 2013.pdf
  - Moving Through Youth Court (Jan 2002).pdf
- Newsletters, 2007-2011; F-1-15; 8 textual records in portable document format (PDF)
  Series consists of the newsletters of the JHSLM.
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2007 Spring.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2008 Fall.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2008 Spring.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2009 Spring.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2009 Winter.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2010 Spring.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2010 Winter.pdf
  - JHSLM Newsletter - 2011 Winter.pdf
- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1996-2013; F-1-16; 30.3 mb of textual records in portable document format (PDF)
  Series consists of the minutes of the Board of Directors for the JHSLM.
  Restricted until December 31, 2026. Beginning January 1st 2027 records will be subject to a review by the archivist for personal information in accordance with the Personal Information Protection Act.
  - 1996 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-1
    Restricted
  - 1997 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-2
  - 1998 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-3
  - 1999 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-4
  - 2000 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-5
  - 2001 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-6
  - 2002 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-7
  - 2003 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-8
  - 2004 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-9
  - 2005 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-10
  - 2006 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-11
  - 2007 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-12
  - 2008 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-13
  - 2009 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-14
  - 2010 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-15
  - 2011 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-16
  - 2012 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-17
  - 2013 Board of Directors meeting minutes, F-1-16-0-0-18